EL HOUSSAINE LAKIOUI

Full Stack Developer

Nationality: MOROCCAN Age: 29 YEARS OLD Family status: married

Full stack developer looking for new challenges. Curious, passionate and motivated to develop my skills and take on challenges. Ready to share my knowledge and learn new technologies.

EXPERIENCE

Developer Symfony Full Stack

FEB 2021 - Jan 2023

EOL ICT - CASABLANCA

- 1. Develop web applications using Symfony, Docker, and Git.
- 2. Troubleshoot technical issues related to web development.
- 3. Implement best practices for code quality assurance.
- 4. Monitor application performance to identify areas of improvement.
- 5. Keep up to date with the latest technology trends and updates in web development.

Consultant Symfony, Sylius

OCT 2019 – NOW

independent consultant

- 1. Analyze client requirements to determine best solution using Symfony and Sylius
- 2. Develop custom web applications utilizing the Symfony framework and Sylius
- 3. Implement Symfony/Sylius standards, conventions, best practices, patterns, etc.
- 4. Troubleshoot application issues and provide technical support when needed
- 5. Setup and configure web servers running Linux, Nginx, and PHP-FPM
- 6. Troubleshoot issues related to web server environment
- 7. Monitor performance of web server environment
- 8. Deploy applications to production
- 9. Security patching of the web server environment
- 10. Develop scripts for automation of tasks
- 11. Ensure availability and reliability of web servers

Full Stack Developer

NOV - 2019 - FEB 2021

NUMERIC WAY - CASABLANCA

- 1. Design, develop, test, deploy, maintain and improve web applications
- 2. Develop client-side code using HTML/CSS/JavaScript/Node.js
- 3. Develop server-side code using Node.js
- 4. Develop database schemas and queries using MySQL/MongoDB
- 5. Troubleshoot and debug applications to ensure they function as expected
- 6. Work with the team lead to define application requirements
- 7. Application deployment (GIT, Capistrano, Docker, VPS)
- 8. Set up DEBIAN web servers, UBUNTU (nginx, PHP cli, PHP FPM, MariaDB)

Web Developer

AUG 2016 - OCT 2019

WEBDEVIA - MEKNES

- 1. Designing user interactions on web pages
- 2. Developing back end website applications
- 3. Creating servers and databases for functionality
- 4. Ensuring responsiveness of applications
- 5. Working alongside graphic designers for web design features

VERSATILE, TENACIOUS, ADAPT QUICKLY.

EDUCATION

Master in Communication Systems and Data Center Management SETTAT FACULTY OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY	2022
Bachelor's degree in development and database EFET GROUP - MEKNES	2019
Web development CADC AL AKHAWAYNE AZROU	2016
Computer Network Technician ISTA IFRANE	2015
Bachelor of Science in Physics LYCÉE TARIK BEN ZIAD À AZROU	2013



CONTACT

PHONE : +212 6 34 41 08 88

E-MAIL: LAKIOUIELHOUSSAINE@GMAIL.COM
LINKEDIN: https://www.linkedin.com/in/elakioui/

SITE WEB: https://hlakioui.github.io/

COMPÉTENCE

Debian Linux System, Ubuntu

AWS code commit, code build, code deploy

Cloud AWS (EC2, EKS, Amazone S3)

Docker, Lando

Php

Symfony

Sylius

C#

Java

Web design

React / Angular

Git - Git Flow

Python

Oracle SQL - MySql

LANGUES

Native Arabic speakers
Technical English
Technical French

PERSONAL SKILLS

trusted
Creative
teamwork
attentive

CENTRE D'INTÉRÊT

COMPUTER SCIENCE FOOTBALL BASKETBALL